ANURAG TRIPATHI

GitHub ♦ Google Scholar
LinkedIn ♦ Medium Blog
♦ nowitsanurag@gmail.com ♦ +91-9818646073

A graduate in Electronics & Communication Engineering with over one year of experience in IT Risk Management and Artificial Intelligence. Proficient with Python and its web frameworks as well as Machine Learning and Deep Learning.

EDUCATION

Amity University 2017 - 2021 Bachelor of Technology Noida, India

- · Department: Electronics and Communication Engineering
- · Relevant courses: Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning, Neural Networks and Deep Learning
- · Thesis: Classification of Cervical cancer using Machine learning and Deep learning (Report)
- · Advisor: Ms. Anupama Bhan
- · GPA: 7.84/10 (First Division)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Com OlhoFeb 2022-PresentProduct ManagerGurgaon, India

- Developed web application back end components with **Django** while communicating with clients to identify their needs/goals and work on meeting them.
- Obtained adequate experience in reviewing Python code for running the troubleshooting test-cases and bug issues.
- · Experienced with front-end technologies, such as HTML, CSS for good UI development.
- · Worked on the improvement of data protection and security by implementing face login using **deep learning** on company's platform.
- · Database knowledge and python interaction with databases.
- · Experienced with **selenium** web-based automation tools and developing under **Linux** environment.
- Designed and developed analysis systems to extract information from large scale data.

Ennoventure Technologies Pvt. Ltd

Software Engineer

Aug 2021- Feb 2022 Bangalore, India

- Experienced with flask framework.
- · Responsible for creating and testing APIs and deploying in **Azure cloud**.
- Updated and optimized 20+ stored procedures using MySQL.
- · Developed SQL stored procedure, functions and style sheets to reduce data retrieval time by 50%.
- · Re-structured schemas with 50+ tables to enhance data integrity.
- · Responsible for training **machine learning** models on the company's patented product for identification when scanned from mobile app.
- · Optimized classification algorithms for applications.

INTERNSHIP EXPERIENCE

Com Olho Feb 2021-June 2021

Research Intern- Data Science

Gurgaon, India

- · Use of high speed **computer vision** to study the effect of vehicular frequency over time to pollution.
- · Implemented vehicle detection at national highway 8 (Gurgaon, India) using OpenCV model.
- · Model was running for 1 month to get the trend of frequency and density of vehicles observed with respect to real time air quality index.
- · Study revealed that 75% of city pollution is contributed by vehicular density.
- · (Certificate)

ClearExamDec 2020-Feb 2021Software DeveloperDelhi, India

- · Extracted and collected data to create needed reports.
- · Design and maintain **SQL** scripts.
- · Validated accuracy of data to ensure database integrity.
- · Created and optimized diverse SQL queries.
- · Generate reports and spreadsheets detailing database changes and performance.
- · (Certificate), (LOR)

PUBLICATIONS

- Anurag Tripathi, A. Arora and A. Bhan, "Classification of Cervical Cancer Detection using Machine Learning Algorithms," 2021 6th International Conference on Inventive Computation Technologies (ICICT), 2021, pp. 827-835, doi: 10.1109/ICICT50816.2021.9358570.
- Anurag Tripathi, A. Arora and A. Bhan, "Classification of cervical cancer using Deep Learning Algorithm," 2021
 5th International Conference on Intelligent Computing and Control Systems (ICICCS), 2021, pp. 1210-1218, doi: 10.1109/ICICCS51141.2021.9432382.
- Reza, M. et al. (2021). Automatic Diabetes and Liver Disease Diagnosis and Prediction through SVM and KNN Algorithms.
 In: Anurag Tripathi, Hassanien, A.E., Bhattacharyya, S. (eds) Emerging Technologies in Data Mining and Information Security. Advances in Intelligent Systems and Computing, vol 1300. Springer, Singapore.
 doi: 10.1007/978-981-33-4367-2 56.
- · Implementation of Machine Learning using Python for Classification of Human Limb Movement using UWB antenna. Classified human limb movement using machine learning with python by fabricating on body ultra-wide band antennas which were used on the human limb to record readings for limb movements. (communicated to JMLR)

PROJECTS

- **Design and fabrication of compact Ultra-Wide Band antenna**. Designed and simulated a compact Ultra-Wideband antenna (29.5 mm x 30 mm) on CST software. Fabricated antenna on PCB; tested in an anechoic chamber. Plotted antennae parameters (S-parameter, polarization, power radiation etc.) from readings obtained deploying a Vector Network Analyzer
- Face-X —Recognition of faces by different algorithms and frameworks. Despite a variety of open-source face
 recognition frameworks available, there was no ready-made solution to implement. In this project all kinds of
 algorithms are implemented and even with various operations that can be implemented in a frontal face. The
 available algorithms processed only high-resolution static shots and performed sufficiently well. (GitHub)
- · Face mask detection using YOLO Algorithm— Detection of face mask using YOLO Algorithm. (Blog)
- · To display deep learning model on Pima Indians onset of diabetes binary classification problem. (Report)
- Developing a CNN for MNIST handwritten digit classification. (Report)

ORGANIZATIONAL WORK

· Coordinating Committee, Celebration of Belongingness. (Certificate)	April - May 2020
· Coordinating Committee, 7 th IEEE SPIN.	March 2020
· Volunteering Committee, 6 th IEEE SPIN. (Certificate)	March 2019
· Volunteering Committee, 5 th IEEE SPIN. (Certificate)	Feb 2018

EXTRA CURRICULAR & SERVICES

JAX Foundation Oct 2020
NGO Volunteering Noida, India

- · Worked on the topic of Cancer Awareness.
- · Working with community program leaders and advocates to make resources available to those in need.
- · Taught unprivileged kids every weekend and introduced them to computers and the internet world.
- · (Certificate), (Report)

Study Abroad ProgramNov-Dec 2019Student Exchange ProgramLondon, UK

- · Attended lectures at Birkbeck, University of London, and Amity University, London for 5 weeks in the 5th semester.
- Opted elective Courses: Global Information Technology (CSIT219) and Understanding Principles & Practices of Commercial Research (IB206)
- In due course also visited Oxford University, Cambridge University, Northampton University, and Brunel University London for attending guest lectures.
- · (Certificate)

Lakshy FoundationApril-Sept 2019NGO VolunteeringUttar Pradesh, India

- · Worked in healthcare and assisted the fundraising team with writing grant proposals.
- Developed and created programs and monitored effectiveness towards individual participants in community workshops to promote various programs and educate the public about needs.
- · Helped to develop an online platform for stray animal adoption.
- · (Experience Letter)

CERTIFICATIONS

· Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python), Michigan University. (Certificate)	Oct 2021
· Databases and SQL for Data Science with Python, <i>IBM</i> . (Certificate)	Sep 2021
· Machine Learning with python, IBM (Certificate)	July 2020
· Getting Started with AWS Machine Learning, AWS. (Certificate)	April 2020
· Machine Learning, Stanford University. (Certificate)	Oct 2019
· Introduction to the Internet of Things (IoT), Alison. (Certificate)	Oct 2019
· Introduction to Data Science , Alison. (<u>Certificate</u>)	Oct 2019
• Deep Learning Prerequisites: The Numpy Stack in Python, Udemy (Certificate)	July 2019

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- · Languages- Python, HTML, MATLAB, C++.
- · Frameworks- Django, Numpy, Flask, Tensor flow
- · Platforms- Git, AWS.
- · OS Linux, Windows

SPOKEN LANGUAGES

- English (Full professional proficiency)
- · Hindi (Mother Tongue)
- French (Elementary proficiency)